# **BYRON POLLEY**

HTTPS://RESUME.BYRONPOLLEY.COM

## Johannesburg, South Africa | byronpolley@live.com | +27832865231

#### **Skills Summary**

Frontend Developer based in Johannesburg, South Africa with multi-disciplinary background in all aspects of web development and familiarity with backend technologies. Primary technologies of interest include React.js and Angular with the intention of creating mobile-friendly experiences using React Native / Swift. Prior experience with UI / UX design instilled a keen design eye into all project deliverables as well as familiarity with media preparation and optimization across all new age formats. Strict on programming best practice through clean and well documented code. Exceptional at writing technical documentation for software and API's. Obsessed with cutting-edge technologies and the possibilities they offer in improving the entire software development lifecycle. Well versed in Agile Methodologies.

#### Education

### Monash University

Bachelor of Computer & Information Sciences | June 2012 – November 2015 Graduated in 2015 with a major in Application Development & Networking and a minor in Business Systems. Course has a strong focus on security, object-orientated design and datastructures / algorithms. Primary language of development was Java.

# Experience

# Cavalry Media | www.hellocavalry.com

Frontend Engineer | April 2018 - Present

Developing web applications primarily in the insurance and financial technology sectors using Angular framework. Working with several notable brands creating Al-driven insurance quote paths. Research and Implementation of new technologies. Platforms include Angular, ExpressionEngine, CraftCMS and Grav. Strong focus on security and data.

## The Bread | www.thebread.co.za

Frontend Developer | June 2016 – March 2018

Developing interactive websites, eCommerce frontends and web applications for a variety of brands / startups and rapidly prototyping in-house projects using current UX approaches. Platforms include WordPress, Shopify, Squarespace and React.js. Strong focus on metrics, usability and performance.